Subhajit Mitra

(.Net Core, Angular, SAP Spartacus)

<u>subhajitmitra.1996@gmail.com</u>

+91 7278226750

in www.linkedin.com/in/subhajit-mitra102

♥ Kolkata, West Bengal

I am a full stack web developer with 5+ years' experience in developing software solutions for enterprises. I have worked on various technology stacks ranging from .NET full stack to SAP Spartacus with Hybris 2205. Actively working on developing and maintaining Cloud native applications.

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS

- ➤ .NET 5 & 7
- > REST API, Entity Framework
- MS SQL Server, Oracle DB
- Azure PaaS (AZ-900 certified)

- Angular 15, Spartacus 6
- > HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Programming Languages: C#, Typescript
- Working with GitHub, Bitbucket, JIRA tool

WORK EXPERIENCE

IBM - Senior Package Consultant (May 2023 to present)

Project Engagement 1 (Spartacus developer – Angular 15):

- Working as a senior front-end developer for building store front of an e-commerce application which has millions of products and works in several countries. The front-end uses SAP Spartacus 6+ and the backend is Hybris 2211.
- Developed and delivered several modules independently end to end. Fixed 100+ critical/high bugs during development and in production. Also provided technical guidance to other junior developers.
- Created technical designs before development and created documentation for developed features.
- Worked extensively to create robust UI components with mobile responsive views.

Accenture - Custom Software Engineering Senior Analyst (July 2021 to May 2023)

Project Engagement 1 (Full Stack developer – .NET core, Angular 12, MSSQL):

- Developed a Cloud Native project for a from scratch using Telerik Kendo UI, AM charts, etc to develop several
 components, implemented routing, lazy loading of the components for performance improvement, implemented
 authentication and integrated services with backend APIs.
- Developed several Web APIs and integrated Azure Blob Storage, Azure AD, application insights to the solution. Worked with MSSQL to write queries and develop stored procedures. Performed manual deployments to App-service.

Project Engagement 2 (Angular12 + Spartacus):

- Working as a Front-end developer for store-front development using Angular 12 for the upgrading a legacy application which was made using Angular JS. The Backend is SAP hybris.
- Involved in development, bug fixes and enhancement activities. Fixed 50+ critical bugs and several other bugs during UAT and post production release.
- Implemented WAI accessibility features using ARIA for improving screen reader ability and keyboard access.

Infosys Limited – Senior Systems Engineer (November 2018 to July 2021)

Project Engagement 1 (.NET Core, Angular):

- Worked on a Cloud based application which uses Microservices architecture. Created APIs using Entity Framework core
 with the backend using Oracle Database.
- Involved in the development of UI components, Web APIs, Microservices, Database tables, Stored Procedures, Triggers and Unit testing.

Project Engagement 2:

 Worked on an ASP.Net MVC Application as a member of the development team, performing enhancements on a regular basis. The project used Asp.NET MVC, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap etc for front-end and MSSQL was used for the database.

EDUCATION

- B. Tech in Civil Engineering from Heritage Institute of Technology, Kolkata | CGPA: 9.38 | 2014-2018
- I.S.C (Class XII) from Xavier's English School Konnagar | Percentage: 90.50% | 2014
- I.C.S.E (Class X) from Xavier's English School Konnagar | Percentage: 90.00% | 2012

OTHER DETAILS

Nationality: Indian | Gender: Male | Language Proficiency: English, Hindi, Bengali